

PERSONAL BACKGROUND

I am a motivated and experienced professional with a bachelor's degree in Science for International Communication and a background in hospitality and customer service.

Working for more than 10 years in the tourism industry, I've recently concluded my working collaboration with an international online travel agency, working as a Customer Experience Specialist and promoted within 5 months due to strong performance and organizational impact.

I have a clear, logical mind with a practical approach to problem-solving. I'm curious and always willing to learn: I like to try new things and have ideas to challenge the status quo. I'm not afraid of mistakes and roll up my sleeves to make things happen.

SKILLS

- Communication and negotiation
- Saling and marketing operations
- Troubleshooting
- Multitasking
- Teamwork
- Time management
- Emotional intelligence
- Organization

EDUCATION

University of Catania

Bachelor's degree in Science for international communication

(Languages spoken: Italian, English, Spanish, French)

Cervantes Institute

Spanish Language Diploma - Intermediate Level - B2

GET IN TOUCH WITH ME

Address: Via A. Algardi, 13 - Milano

Cell: +39 3475920099 Email: marypitta@hotmail.it

Skype: marypitta

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/maria-pitta

MARIA PITTÀ

Tourism / Customer Service

WORK EXPERIENCES

Specialized Support Team

Agoda International Hungary Kft - Futò utca 34-36, Corvin Center Budapest, Hungary

March 2020 - July 2021

- Dedicated L2 agent assigned to handle specialized procedures
- · Handle partner/supplier's requests, supporting the Italian, English and Spanish market
- Mentoring session for junior agents

Customer Experience Specialist

Agoda International Hungary Kft - Eiffel Square Office Building B, Teréz krt. 55 - Budapest, Hungary

Oct 2019 - March 2020

- Deliver excellent customer service and manage the customer's needs (guests and partners)
- Understand and deliver business strategies and improve customer services through the execution of self-service
- Accountable for meeting individual and team goals (KPIs)
- Continuously identify work process improvements and communicate to Team Leaders and (or) Managers.
- Programmes used: Genesys, Athena, Sharepoint

Receptionist & Back office executive

Suite Inn srl - Via Vittorio Emanuele II 108 - Catania, Italy Nov 2014 - Sept 2019

- Responsible for all the operations of front and back-office: welcoming guests, dealing with
 reservations by phone and emails, manage online travel agencies Extranets, manage prices and
 availability using channel manager Hotelbb.
- Web marketing operations: web and competitor analysis using Google Analytics, SEO operations, editing website content using CSM Joomla platform, managing social platforms content (Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, Instagram, Foursquare).

Receptionist & Guest Relations

Mezzoroma restaurant - 66 Walm Ln, Willesden - London, UK Nov 2013 - May 2014

- Welcoming guests and handle their requests
- Take reservations by phone and emails
- Managing food orders through dedicated software
- Cashiering operations

Receptionist

Catania City Center - Via Naumachia 103 - Catania, Italy Jun 2010 - Nov 2013

- Front and back-office operations: welcoming guests, dealing with reservations by phone and emails, managing online travel agencies extranet, respond to customers' reviews, accounting operations
- Responsible to create contents for social media platforms

Excursions & Tour Organizer

Etna Experience - Piazza Federico di Svevia 32 - Catania, Italy Jan 2013 - Jun 2014

- In charge of organizing excursions around Sicily.
- Managing reservations by phone and e-mails, coordinating tour guides according to guests'
- To be the point of contact for travel agencies and hotels